Guide to the Terence Sellers Papers 1967-2000 MSS.167
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series V: Photographic Materials
  - Negatives of "Mistress Angel" by Chuck Sillery, undated (Binder 3, Folder 432)
  - Contact sheets and negatives by Seth Tillet of Terence Sellers., [1980] (Binder 3, Folder 433)
  - Contact sheets, negatives and stills from "The Film that was Never Made" by Gordon Stevenson, 1980-1981 (Binder 3, Folder 434)
  - Still photographs from film by Harold Vogel, 1984-1985 (Binder 3, Folder 435)
  - Photographic prints of Terence Sellers by Marti Wilkerson, 1997 (Binder 3, Folder 436)
  - Photographic prints, negatives, and slides of Terence Sellers by unknown photographers, various (Binder 3, Folder 437)
  - Slides: Terence Sellers, Green Nude on Beach (photographer unknown), 1975 (Binder 3, Folder 437 A)
  - Negatives and Photograph: Beach-Grandma, Angel Stern (photographer unknown), 1988 (Binder 3, Folder 437 B)
  - Slides for Stern Magazine (Germany). Terence Sellers as "whore", Jeffrey Bretschneider as "pimp" (photographer unknown), c.1983 (Binder 3, Folder 437 C)
  - Negatives: Paris and Venice (photographer unknown), 1974 (Binder 3, Folder 437 D)
  - Matted 8x10 photograph of Terence Sellers by unknown photographer, undated (Box 15, Folder 438)
- Series VI: Business
  This series contains business related documents and materials related to Seller's career in New York City as Angel Stern.
  - "Book of Beasts", 1989-1991 (Box 15, Folder 439)
  - Client Cards, 1980s-2000 (Box 15, Folder 440)
  - Client Cards, continued, 1980s-2000 (Box 15, Folder 441)
  - Client Cards, continued, 1980s-2000 (Box 15, Folder 442)
  - Client Cards, continued, 1980s-2000 (Box 15, Folder 443)
  - Client Cards, continued, 1980s-2000 (Box 15, Folder 444)
  - Client Cards, continued, 1980s-2000 (Box 15, Folder 445)
  - Client Cards, continued, 1980s-2000 (Box 15, Folder 446)
  - Financial Ledger, 1982 (Box 15, Folder 452)
  - Financial Notes, undated (Box 15, Folder 453)
  - Mistress Cards, 1980s-1990s (Box 15, Folder 454)
  - "Stan Book", 1992-1993 (Box 15, Folder 455)
  - Terence Sellers AKA Angel Stern, original envelope with annotations., undated (Box 15, Folder 456)
  - Timesheets, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 457)
  - Timesheets, continued, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 458)
  - Old Rules of the House, 1983-1989 (Box 50, Folder 22)
- Series VII: Academic and Biographical Materials
  Series includes materials relating to Sellers college studies and personal biographical information.
  - Materials from this folder have been moved to Series I, Folder 127C, 1946 (Box 11, Folder 459)
  - Author's Resume, 1977-1988 (Box 11, Folder 460)
  - Categories on Interpretation of Prior Analytics, undated (Box 11, Folder 461)
  - Cratylus, St. Augustine, Sophist, undated (Box 11, Folder 462)
  - Grec Autres Poesus, undated (Box 11, Folder 463)
  - Greek Notebooks, undated (Box 11, Folder 464)
  - Greek Notebooks, undated (Box 11, Folder 465)
  - Mistress Sterling, The Chameleon, undated (Box 11, Folder 466)
  - Nietzche Notes, undated (Box 11, Folder 467)
  - Notes from "Rhetoric of Eros: De Sade and Sacher Masoch", undated (Box 11, Folder 468)
  - Notes on Dispersement of Manuscripts, 1995-1996 (Box 9, Folder 469)
  - Resume, 1993-1994 (Box 9, Folder 470)
  - Sociology Papers, 1983-1984 (Box 11, Folder 471)
  - "Trix of the Trade" in The Face, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 472)
- Series VIII: Media
  This series includes audiocassettes that Sellers recorded in the 1970s. Materials include a recorded interview with Jimmy De Sana for Vacation Magazine in 1981 as well as recordings of Sellers reading her own poems and text from her published writing.
  - Subseries A: Sound recordings
    Conditions Governing Access
    Access copies for some materials are available by appointment for reading room viewing and listening only. Please contact fales.library@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596.
    - Poem, Radio Music, Disposable Epidermis '73; Susan and Terry Being 'tots' '73, Valium-Cool poem, Gangster of Love, other bad poems, Mark reading poems '74, 1973-1974; ID: 167.0001 (Box 14, Media ID: 167.0001, Case 167.0001)
      Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
      Original format: Audiocassette. Brand Unknown, Tape Capacity Unknown
      Existence and Location of Copies
      CD access copy available.
      Currently available.
    - Neil and Terence Deranged Radio Show, Paranoid Mabel, and Frank as Feces Poet; Obsession reading, 1973;1976; ID: 167.0002 (Box 14, Cassette 167.0002)
      Original format: Audiocassette. Hitachi C-120; The tape is damaged and has not been digitized.
      Currently unavailable
    - Interview with Jimmy de Sana for VACATION, "Foreigner" dialogue between Eric Mitchell and T.S.; The Cannibal Mouth, 1981; ID: 167.0003 (Box 14, Media ID: 167.0003, Case 167.0003)
      Original format: Audiocassette, Scotch C-60
    - Impotence Con't; Ennui, Alice Cooper. First Night with Jules, L'Azur par Mallarme, To Libertines, Marquis de Sade, January 6, 1977; 1973; ID: 167.0004 (Box 14, Media ID: 167.0004, Case 167.0004)
      Original format: Audiocassette, Memorex AD 60
    - Alexander Weinstock Incident, related to Marie Stanley ms; Correct Sadist early text overlaid with poems... Part III, 1974;1978; ID: 167.0005 (Box 14, Media ID: 167.0005, Case 167.0005)
    - Obscene Phone Calls, Fire Dream (con't), undated; ID: 167.0006 (Box 14, Media ID: 167.0006, Case 167.0006)
      Original format: Audiocassette, Memorex 60
    - Interview with Jerzy Skolimowski, November 9, 1979; ID: 167.0007 (Box 14, Media ID: 167.0007, Case 167.0007)
      Original format: Audiocassette, TDK D-C90
    - The Correct Sadist - Excerpts - Reading, May 18, 1980; ID: 167.0008 (Box 14, Media ID: 167.0008, Case 167.0008)
      Original format: Audiocassette, Data Packaging Dictation D-60
- Series IX: Computer Disks
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains two disks of photographic material from Terence Sellers' collaboration with Jimmy de Sana on his "Submission" project.
  - Subseries A: Computer Media
    Born-digital materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers.
    - Jimmy de Sana "Submission" Outtakes (Mac version), 1978-9; ID 167.0009 (Box 14, Media ID 167.0009)
      Format: Data CD
      Currently not available.
    - Jimmy de Sana "Submission" Outtakes (PC version), 1978-9; ID 167.0010 (Box 14, Media ID 167.0010)
- OVERSIZE Series IV: Writing
  - Subseries B: Book-length Works
    - The Correct Sadist: Promotional Materials, unknown (Box 12, Folder 246 A)
    - The Correct Sadist: Times Square Show Reading, poster, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 261 B)
    - The Obsession: Boards, 1985-1986 (Box 9, Folder 356 B)
  - Subseries E: Publications
    - BOMB, vol.1, issue 1, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 399)
    - BOMB, vol.1, issue 2, 1982 (Box 12, Folder 400)
    - BOMB, no.4, 1982 (Box 12, Folder 401)
    - East Village Eye Vol.5, No.44, 1984 (Box 12, Folder 404)
    - FAD, undated (Box 12, Folder 405)
    - File Magazine, Vol.3, No.4, 1977 (Box 15, Folder 407)
    - Impulse, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 410)
    - Screw, No. 1276, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 412)
    - Screw, No. 1479, 1997 (Box 12, Folder 413)
    - Screw, No. 1480 (Box 12, Folder 414)
    - Article from Soldes de Fin de Series, No. 6, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 416)
    - Soldes Magazine, 1979-80 (Box 12, Folder 417)
    - Vacation, No. 4, 1980 (Box 12, Folder 418)
    - X Magazine, Vol. 2, Issues 2-3, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 420)
    - X Magazine, Vol.2, issues 4-6, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 421)
- OVERSIZE Series V: Photographic Materials
  - Prints, some taken by George Du Bose of Terence Sellers., ca. 1982 (Box 12, Folder 426 A)
  - BUY Contortions LP, Cover photograph by Anya Philips, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 430A)
  - Photo-collage of Terence "Suffering From Ennui at the Pink Teacup", ca. 1970s (Box 12)
- OVERSIZE Series VI: Business
  - Desk Calendars, November 1983-August 1984, 1983-1984 (Box 13, Folder 447)
  - Desk Calendars, February 1985-December 1987, 1985-1987 (Box 13, Folder 448)
  - Desk Calendars, January-December, 1988 (Box 13, Folder 449)
  - Desk Calendars, January-October, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 450)
  - Desk Calendars, January 1990-September 1992, 1990-1992 (Box 13, Folder 451)
- Series X: Unprocessed Accretions
  - Accession 2016.011, 2016.011; 7 Linear Feet In 6 record cartons and 1 flat oversized box (Box 16, Box 17, Box 18, Box 19, Box 20, Box 21, Box 22)
    Scope and Content
    This accretion includes items created by and collected by Terence Sellers over the course of her adult life. Content related to Sellers artistic practice include correspondence, published and unpublished manuscripts, personal items, diaries, notebooks, flyers, drawings and etchings. Materials include copies of an unpublished manuscript (referred to as "unpublished novel") and Seller's favorite leather gloves and leather cuffs, worn in the author photo of The Correct Sadist. Materials collected by Sellers include published and unpublished writings, as well as drawings by Carl Apfelschnitt and a draft of an unpublished novel written by Sellers' father that inspired her own work.
  - Accession 2016.025, 1912-2015; 30 Linear Feet in 22 record cartons, 4 oversize boxes, and 1 manuscript box (Box 23, Box 24, Box 25, Box 26, Box 27, Box 28, Box 29, Box 30, Box 31, Box 32, Box 33, Box 34, Box 35, Box 36, Box 37, Box 38, Box 39, Box 40, Box 41, Box 42, Box 43, Box 44, Box 45, Box 46, Box 47, Box 48, Box 49)
    This accretion is comprised of materials collected by Sellers related to magic, the occult (particularly the works of Aleister Crowley), vampires, the zodiac, the history and practices of sex work, bondage, sadism and masochism, Nazis and the history of medical experimentation, the history of drug use in medicine and pop culture, psychology, fashion, New York club and goth culture, criminology, satanism, serial killers, esoteric thought and spirituality, and modern and contemporary art. Materials include books, press clippings, articles, manuscripts, journals and sketchbooks, correspondence, plays, implements such as a bull whip, shoes, and leather mask, VHS tapes, zip disks, cassette tapes, CD-R, original artwork and sketches, stencils, magazines, erotica, tarot cards, and photographs. Also included are posters and a matchbook display rack.
    Sadomasochism |v Fiction.; Enochian magic.; Leather lifestyle.; Criminology.; Occultism.; Books.; Sexual dominance and submission.; Crowley, Aleister, 1875-1947
- Unprocessed Materials (Folder oversize folder, Item 2, Folder oversize box folder x)